# **Georgios Kormpakis**

COMPUTER ENGINEER - SOFTWARE ENGINEER/DEVELOPER

Address: Sarantaporou 5, Ilioupoli, Athens, 16346 Email: kormpakisgeorgios@gmail.com Telephone: (+30) 6989126885 GitHub: kormpakis LinkedIn: Giorgos Kormpakis				
Personal Statement ————————————————————————————————————				
Hello! My name is Georgios Kormpakis and I am a passionate Software Engineer-Developer. In my career so far, I have mostly worked in the Front End, which is, as I found out, something that I love.				
I like new challenges, I strive for perfection, I am a fan of minimalism and I love being				

part of a team, of something "bigger than me". I am an active person, pleasant,

Work history

### **PhD Student**

# **EPU of the Decision Support Systems Laboratory, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, NTUA**

October 2021 - Now

hardworking and ambitious.

After one year of working experience in EPU-NTUA, I was accepted as a PhD Student, due to my work in energy-research projects.

The subject of my PhD is: Intelligent online support systems for energy services

# **Software Engineer/Developer - Junior Researcher**

# **EPU of the Decision Support Systems Laboratory, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, NTUA**

October 2020 - Now

EPU-NTUA is a multidisciplinary scientific unit which carries out research and development activities providing management and decision support services on a wide range of complex business, societal and technical problems.

EPU-NTUA collaborates regularly in R&D and technical assistance projects with several major Greek, European and international organisations. It is involved in major EU programmes as well as in national programmes funded by Greek Ministries (National Economy, Industry, Energy and Technology, Environment and Urban Planning), Energy

Organisations (electricity, oil, and gas sectors), regional and national authorities, and other public and private organisations.

During this period, I have participated in a number of interesting research projects. My responsibilities have been various. I participated in both the development and partially in the decision-making of the aforementioned projects and I also contributed to several deliverables.

Working in EPU-NTUA, I have made usage of several technologies, including **React**, **Django** and **Drupal**, as well as numerous libraries with several usages (e.g., **amCharts** for visualizations, **MaterialUI** as a front-end framework, etc.). I have also been involved in Security Mechanism Design (**UMA 2**, **OAuth 2.0**), by leveraging tools like **KeyCloak**. Finally, I have designed several back-end applications, using **Node.js**.

## **Software Engineer-Developer**

### **Synelixis Solutions**

November 2019 – September 2020

I joined Synelixis Solutions right after completing my military service, as a Junior Software Engineer-Developer. Synelixis Solutions is a respectful, greek company, which has its own products and also participates in research projects, mostly funded by the European Union.

During these months, I have been working mostly in four projects, mainly in the Front End. I have worked in **Vue.js** and **React**, using also **Next.js** in order to achieve server-side rendering in the last project. I have also used WordPress in my current job.

During this period, I have been trained to use these tools and frameworks and I have also worked efficiently under extreme pressure, when a big project had to be delivered in a very small amount of time. This project was delivered to the Greek government, and it was a big challenge, not only programmatically, but also as a test of how efficiently and quickly all the colleagues could cooperate. I also had the opportunity to plan, organize and run a promotional campaignfor my company's new product, a social media app.

#### **Editor in Chief**

## Rock Rooster. gr

2014 - 2019

I have been the founder, designer, chief editor and contact manager of the Greek website RockRooster.gr, one of the most popular websites about music and cinema in the country. During these years, I designed the website, using WordPress, and had the chance to cooperate with recognized artists and the largest festivals and venues in Greece.

#### Intern

### Bank of Greece (Patras branch)

2016-2017

Internship at the accounting department of Bank of Greece's Patras branch (6 months + 6 months after contract renewal).

**Education & Training** 

## **Computer Engineering and Informatics Department**

### **University of Patras**

2010-2018

Five-year studies equivalent to a master's degree according to the European standards (300 ECTS).

Thesis: Web content adjustment based on users' navigation habits

**Grade:** 10/10

Short Description: My thesis involved developing an Android application and serverside software development (plugins for WordPress). It also involved the creation of an experimental Ontology, as an alternative approach to the problem of setting up recommendation systems.

#### **Further Education**

I have attended various courses about Vue.js, React.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Django Rest Framework, Python, etc. All the courses can be seen in my LinkedIn profile.

**Main Publications** 

# I-NERGY: Delivering the next-generation Artificial Intelligence services for the Energy Sector

Georgios Lampropoulos, Sotiris Pelekis, Vagelis Karakolis, Gerasimos Anastasatos, Georgios Kormpakis, Ioannis Tsapelas, Spyridon Mouzakitis, Vangelis Marinakis, John Psarras Link: <a href="https://www.euro-online.org/conf/euro31/treat\_abstract?paperid=1343">https://www.euro-online.org/conf/euro31/treat\_abstract?paperid=1343</a>

# **Enabling Maritime Digitalisation through the use of extreme-scale Artificial Intelligence services**

Ioannis Tsapelas, Georgios Kormpakis, Christos Tsapelas, Georgios Lampropoulos, Spyridon Mouzakitis, Dimitrios Askounis

Link: https://www.euro-online.org/conf/euro31/treat\_abstract?paperid=1465

### **Leveraging Graph Analytics for Energy Efficiency Certificates**

P Kapsalis, G Kormpakis, K Alexakis, D Askounis - Energies 15 (4), 1500 Link: https://www.mdpi.com/1996-1073/15/4/1500

# MATRYCS — A Big Data Architecture for Advanced Services in the Building Domain

M Pau, P Kapsalis, Z Pan, G Korbakis, D Pellegrino, A Monti - Energies 15 (7), 2568 Link: <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/1996-1073/15/7/2568">https://www.mdpi.com/1996-1073/15/7/2568</a>

# An Advanced Visualisation Engine with Role-Based Access Control for Building Energy Visual Analytics

G Kormpakis, P Kapsalis, K Alexakis, S, E Karakolis, H Doukas – IISA Conference 2022 (Proceedings pending)

Skills —					
	'				
≈	Front End (React, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js,	*	Back End (Django, Node.js)		
	WordPress, Drupal)	*	Team player with strong communication		
≈	Ability to work at a fast-paced		skills		
	environment	≈	Strong analytical and problem solving		
≈	Programming Languages I am		skills		
	familiar with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript	≈	IDEs I am familiar with: WebStorm,		
	(incl. ES6), C, C++, Java, Python, PHP,		PyCharm, Android Studio, Visual		
	MySQL, SPARQL, OWL.		Studio, WAMP Server, Protégé,		
			Postman.		
Foreign Languages  Excellent knowledge of English (Michigan Proficiency (ECPE)).					
	Interests				

Leisure time Interests: Sports (watching and playing since I was a child), music, concerts, cinema and generally anything related to cultural events.